--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
w
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
ww
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.H
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HD
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDc
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcm
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcmc
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcmct
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcmct.
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcmct.c
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcmct.co
招募Q号:76846146
--==CMCT团队 荣誉出品==--
影片压制: 九洲客  字幕调校: 子贺居士
www.HDcmct.com
招募Q号:76846146
What are you doing there, fella?
你们在这干什么 哥们?
I just cut these.
我就是割这些
You better come along with us.
你最好和我们一起来
Taking it off here, Boss.
老板 在这放?
Yeah, take it off, Dragline.
是的 放吧 拖绳
- Wiping it off here, Boss? - All right, Koko, wipe it off.
- 老板 这擦掉? - 好的 芋头 擦掉它
Drinking it up here, Boss.
老板 在这喝
All right, drink it up, Gambler.
好的 在这喝 赌鬼
You eyeballing there, Society?
你在盯那里 社会?
Checking my yo-yo, Boss.
看看我的溜溜 老板
Drag, new-meat bus.
拖绳 新犯人的巴士
Bunch. Must be half a dozen new-meat.
一堆 肯定有半打的新犯人
No more than five, for a cold drink.
不超过5个 赌杯饮料
All right, you men get lined up there.
好了 你们在那站好队
Dogboy, shut them dogs up.
狗娃 让那些狗别叫了
They just smell new-meat, s'all, Boss.
他们就是闻到有新犯人而以 老板
What did they bring us today?
他们今天给我们带什么来了?
Gibson, 507 manslaughter.
吉尔什 507 杀人犯
Good for a two spot.
两点区不错
It was an accident. I've never been in trouble before.
是个意外 我以前都没有过问题的
You call the Captain, "Captain."
你叫队长 "队长"
Edgar Potter, 302 and resisting arrest.
埃德加 庖特 302 和据捕
One year.
一年
I was trying to keep in out of the rain.
我那时想在里面躲雨的
Get the wax out of your ears. You call the Captain, "Captain."
把你的耳屎掏干净 你叫队长 "队长"
And you call the rest of us "Boss," you hear?
你叫我们其余的"老板" 听清楚了吗?
This man is going to make us proud of him, Mr. Hunnicutt.
这人会让我们引以为豪的 哈尼卡特先生
Raymond Pratt.
雷蒙德 普莱特
Yes, Captain.
是 队长
Breaking, entering, and assault.
破坏 入室 攻击
Five spot.
5点
And a seaman.
和水手
'Spect that should come in real handy around here, Captain.
怀疑在这会很有用 队长
Maybe.
可能
Lucas Jackson.
卢卡斯 杰克逊
Here, Captain.
到 队长
Maliciously destroying municipal property while under the influence.
酒后恶意破坏政府财产
What was that?
那是什么?
Cutting the heads off parking meters, Captain.
把停车计价器割了 队长
We ain't never had one of them before.
我们以前从没有过这样的人
Where do you think that's going to get you?
你认为放到哪里?
I guess you could say I wasn't thinking, Captain.
我想你可以说我没想 队长
It says here that you did real good in the war.
档案说你在仗争中干的很好
A Silver Star, Bronze Star, couple of Purple Hearts...
一颗银质星章 一颗铜质星章 还有几个紫色奖章...
...Sergeant. Then came out the same way you went in.
...中士 然后和你进去时一样了
Buck Private.
士兵
Like I was just passing time, Captain.
好像我在快越时空 队长
Well, you got yourself some time now...two years.
现在 你有时间了 两年
Well, hell, that ain't much.
嗯 妈的 没多长
We got a couple of men here doing 20 spots.
我们这有人做20点
We got one that's got all of it.
我们有一个全部都有的
We got all kinds, and you're going to fit in real good.
我们全部都有 你会很适合那里的
Of course, in case you get rabbit in your blood...
当然 如果你有兔子的血缘...
...and you decide to take off for home, you get a bonus of some time...
...并且你决定回家的话 你又时候得到奖励...
...and a set of leg chains to keep you slowed down just a little bit.
...一副腿链来让你慢一点点
For your own good, you'll learn the rules.
为了你自己 你会学到规矩的
It's all up to you.
全都看你了
Now I can be a good guy or I can be one real mean son of a bitch.
我可以是个好人或者我可以是个刻薄的龟儿子
It's all up to you.
全都看你了
All right, let's move it.
好了 走吧
One at a time. Move it!
一个一个的来 走!
Them clothes got laundry numbers on them.
这些衣服上有号码
You remember your number and always wear the ones that has your number.
你记住你的号码并且总是穿你自己的号码
Any man forgets his number spends a night in the box.
有人忘记了他的号码就关黑屋子一天
These here spoons you keep with you.
这里有勺子你保管好
Any man loses his spoon spends a night in the box.
有人掉了他的勺子就关黑屋子一天
There's no playing grab-ass or fighting in the building.
不准在室内抢东西或者打架
You got a grudge against another man, you fight him Saturday afternoon.
你和另外一个人有不满 你和他在星期六下午打
Any man playing grab-ass or fighting in the building spends a night in the box.
有人在室内抢东西或者打架就关黑屋子一天
First bell's at five minutes of eight when you will get in your bunk.
第一道铃是在8点差5分 那时你要上床
Last bell is at eight.
最后一道铃是在8点
Any man not in his bunk at eight spends the night in the box.
有人在八点没上床就关黑屋子一天
There is no smoking in the prone position in bed.
不准斜在床上抽烟
To smoke you must have both legs over the side of your bunk.
要吸烟就必须双脚着床
Any man caught smoking prone in bed...
有人斜在床上吸烟...
...spends a night in the box.
...就关黑屋子一天
You get two sheets.
你有两条床单
Every Saturday, you put the clean sheet on the top...
每个星期六 你把干净的床单放在面上...
...the top sheet on the bottom...
...上面的垫下面...
...the bottom sheet you turn in to the laundry boy.
...下面的你给洗衣服的
Any man turns in the wrong sheet spends a night in the box.
给错的人就关黑屋子一天
No one'll sit in the bunks with dirty pants on.
不准穿脏裤子坐在床上
Any man with dirty pants on sitting on the bunks spends a night in the box.
有人穿脏裤子坐床上就关黑屋子一天
Any man don't bring back his empty pop bottle spends a night in the box.
有人不还瓶子的就关黑屋子一天
Any man loud talking spends a night in the box.
有人大声说话就关黑屋子一天
You got questions, you come to me.
有问题的话 你来找我
I'm Carr, the floor walker. I'm responsible for order in here.
我叫卡尔 这层楼的巡视 我负责这里的次序
Any man don't keep order spends a night in...
有人不遵守次序就关一天 ...
...the box.
...黑屋子
I hope you ain't going to be a hard case.
我希望你不会是个麻烦
Ain't but four. What did I tell you? You owe me a cold drink.
没有只有四个 我怎么告诉你的? 你欠我一杯饮料
I owe you. I owe you.
我欠你 我欠你
Hey, any of you guys from Connecticut?
喂 你们有人来自康涅狄格吗?
Forget it.
算了吧
Wash them up!
给他们洗洗!
Well, what are you still doing here? Get at them beans!
嗯 你还在这里干什么? 给他们些豆子!
Next time you stay out of my place.
下次你离我的地方远点
You try that again and I'll bounce you off the floor.
你再来的话我把你踢下楼去
Well, man, I didn't know it was your special seat.
嗯 哥们 我不知道这是你的专座
You don't take another man's seat, man.
你别坐别人的座位 哥们
It wasn't his fault. Nobody said anything...
不是他的错 没人说什么...
You better mind you manners, boy. You're acting like a hillbilly tramp.
你最好注意你的态度 孩子 你象堆牛粪
"Tramp." There you go, Beauty.
"牛粪" 给你 美人
Hey, yeah, man, you got your bull-gang name now.
喂 哥们 你现在有名了
Yeah, well, it ain't no worse than some I been called.
是的 没比我以前有过的名字更糟糕
When I was in the Navy...
当我还在海军的时候...
All you new-meats...
所有你们新人...
...you're going to have to shape up fast and hard for this gang.
...你们必须尽快站起来对付这伙人
We got rules here.
我们这有规矩
In order to learn them...
为了学习它们...
...you gotta do more work with your ears than your mouth.
...你得多用耳朵而不是嘴巴
Somebody say something?
有人说什么了吗?
No, I didn't say nothing, Boss.
没 我没说什么 老板
What have we got there?
我们这有些什么人?
Got a Lucas Jackson.
有个卢卡斯 杰克逊
You don't have a name here until Dragline gives you one.
直到拖绳给你取名 你在这没有名字
Maybe we ought to call it No-Ears. You don't listen much, do you, boy?
也许我们得叫它没耳朵 你听不进很多 是吗 孩子?
I ain't heard that much worth listening to.
我没听见有很多值得听得
A lot of guys laying down a lot of rules and regulations.
很多人定下了很多的规矩和条款
New-meat looks like a poker player, Drag.
新人看起来像个打扑克牌的 拖绳
Yeah, that wouldn't surprise me none.
是的 没什么让我吃惊的
I know you've got five dollars pocket money.
我知道你口袋里有5块钱
That would buy you a whole fistful of cards. You in or out?
你可以买一把牌 玩还是不玩?
Out.
不玩
First bell.
第一道铃
How'd you get that scar?
你那块疤怎么来的?
What scar?
什么疤?
Last bell.
最后一道铃
Fifty, Boss.
五十 老板
Right, Carr. Fifty.
对 卡尔 五十
Getting up here, Carr.
上来这里 卡尔
Get out of my eyeballing seat, you new-meat dummy.
从我盯人的位子上滚开 你个新来的傻帽
I'm a salesman. I used to drive these roads all the time.
我是个推销商 我过去老是在那些路上开着车
Drag, it's going to be one hot mother today.
托绳 今天会是个妈的很热的天
Yeah, I reckon the Bear's going to be walking the road today.
是的 我想熊今天会在路上走
Then I'm lucky I got me a broom.
那么我就走运了我拿了把扫把
I work on top, real cush job. I would hate to be down in that ditch today.
我在上面做事 真正的轻松活 我会恨今天去那个沟里的
We work in a ditch?
我们在沟里做事?
What's the matter with you?
你怎么啦?
All your big-time driving around, you never seen a chain gang before?
你原来到处逛的时候 你从来没见过苦力囚犯?
I ain't used to hard work, neither. I always tried to avoid it.
我也不适应做苦力 我总是试图避开
I ain't exactly crazy about it, myself.
我自己也不是很喜欢这
Well, man, it's going to be one tough day to learn on.
嗯 哥们 今天会学的很辛苦
Why don't you give one of these new-meat a break...
你为什么不放过这新来的...
...and let him use your broom today?
...让他今天用你的扫把?
Oh, hell, Society, I ain't going down in that ditch.
哦 滚把 社会 我才不去那沟里呢
Well, I sure would appreciate it. I ain't in too good a shape right now.
嗯 我肯定会很感激你的 我现在身体不是很好
Hey, Koko, you really going to sell your job?
喂 芋头 你真的打算卖你的活?
Well, Drag, I may have to.
嗯 托绳 我可能得
Maybe that Lucas War Hero would give you your price.
可能那个卢卡斯战争英雄会付你要的价钱
I'll give you 50 cents.
我给你五十美分
Fifty cents for a sweet job like that? That's worth at least a buck.
五十美分来买这样的美差? 怎么也值至少一美元
I'll make it a dollar.
我会付一美元
Dollar's a deal.
成交
Where'd you get that about war hero?
你从哪里知道关于那个战争英雄的?
A little birdie told me.
一只小鸟告诉我的
Tearing the heads off of...what was it?
把那个鸟头给拧了 是什么?
Gumball machines?
警灯?
What kind of thing is that for a grown man?
那对个成人来说是什么?
You know how it is. Small town. Not much to do in the evening.
你知道是怎么样的 小镇 晚上没什么来做
Mostly was just settling an old score.
多数就是算旧账
Boss, I made this arrangement with this man to take his broom.
老板 我安排这个人来接替他的扫把
- You don't understand, I made this deal. - Get moving.
- 你没明白 我做了这个交易 - 快走
But I made this arrangement.
但是我安排了
Get to work.
去干活
Better take it easy. You won't last two hours.
最好慢慢来 你支持不了2个小时的
Taking it off here, Boss?
老板 在这里开始?
Yeah, Dragline, take it off there.
是的 托绳 在这开始
- Taking it off here, Boss? - Take it off.
- 老板 可以在这开始了? - 开始
Drinking it up here, Boss?
老板 在这喝?
Man bear-clawed here, Boss!
老板 这有熊爪印!
All right, men.
好了 大家
Let's eat them beans!
给他们吃豆子!
Cold drink he don't make it.
他没做饮料
He won't.
他不会
Hey, Babalugats, got a bet here.
喂 芭芭鲁嘎次 打个赌
- Boss, drinking it up here. - Right.
- 老板 在这喝 - 对
Who's that?
那是谁?
That's Godfrey.
那是高德弗雷
The Walking Boss.
巡视老板
Don't he ever talk?
他从来都不说话?
Think he just said somethin'.
我想他刚说了什么
You owe that fella a cold drink.
你欠那个家伙一杯饮料
All right!
好的!
You, Gibson, step out.
你 吉尔什 站出来
Boss Paul says you wasn't happy with your job.
保罗老板说你不喜欢你的活
Says you was complaining.
说你在抱怨
Well, we going to give you a chance to think about it.
嗯 我们打算给你个机会来想想
All right.
好的
Let's go.
走吧
Get them clothes off.
把衣服脱了
First bell.
第一道铃
Plumb busted out. Looks like the hard road finally got to Mr. Lucas War Hero.
铅锤发作了 看来卢卡斯战争英雄先生要倒霉了
I'll be back at it in the morning. Just need a little nap.
我早晨再来说这事 就是想睡一会了
Man, I never thought they'd put him in the box on his first day.
我从来没想到他们会在第一天就把他关黑屋子
It was only supposed to be a joke.
只是一个笑话的
There ain't no brooms.
那也没有扫把
Well, can't expect to learn everything the first day.
嗯 别指望在第一天就学到所有的
They've taught him a very valuable lesson.
他们教了他个非常宝贵的课
You guys sure give him all night to think about it.
你们肯定个了他一个晚上来想这个问题
We can't help it if he's square. Huh, Drag?
如果他那么不识时务我们也没办法 对吧 托绳?
Of course not. He ain't in the box because of a joke played on him.
当然不是 他不是因为被开了个玩笑而被关黑屋子的
He back-sassed a free man.
他关了个自由人
They got their rules and we ain't got nothing to do with that.
他们又他们的规矩 我们没办法
Probably happen to him sooner or later anyway, complainer like him.
象他这样的抱怨 很可能迟早发生在他身上的
He's gotta learn the rules, same as anybody else.
他得和大家一样学会那些规矩
Yeah, them poor old bosses need all the help they can get.
是的 那些可怜的老老板需要所有可能的帮助
Trying to say something?
要说什么?
Last bell!
最后一道铃!
One of these days I'm gonna have to flap me up some dust with it.
有一天 我要用这打打灰尘
- Forty-nine and one in the box, Boss. - Right, Carr, 49 and one in the box.
- 49和一个在黑屋子 老板 - 对 卡尔 49和一个在黑屋子
Putting them on here, Boss.
把它们放在这 老板
You see that, you see that?
你看到了 你看到了?
I got eyes, don't I?
我有眼睛 对吗?
How am I not going to see someone that looks like that?
有人象那样我怎么可能看不到?
Man, oh, man, look at that. Look at that!
哦 看那 看那!
- Wipin' it off here, Boss. - Wipe it off.
- 老板 在这擦 - 擦掉它
- Taking them off here, Boss? - All right.
- 老板 在这里拿掉? - 好的
Damn thing's blocking the scenery.
妈的挡住了
Oh man, I'm dying. I'm dying!
哦 我要死了 我要死了!
Nice broad.
很开阔
Great set.
不错
Lucille, baby.
露西尔 宝贝
Oh man, I'm dying! I'm dying!
哦 我要死了 我要死了!
She ain't got nothing, but...one safety pin holding that thing on!
她没得到什么 但是 保险拴挡住了!
Come on, safety pin, pop!
快点 保险拴!
C'mon baby, pop!
快来 宝贝!
Hey, Lord...
喂 上帝...
...whatever I done, don't strike me blind for another couple of minutes.
...不管我做过什么 别让我又瞎几分钟
My Lucille.
我的露西尔
Your Lucille, boy. Where did you get that?
你的露西尔 你从哪里搞到的?
That's Lucille, you mother-head.
那是露西尔 你个蠢蛋
Anything so innocent, and built like that...
任何那么纯洁的 象那样的...
...just gotta be named Lucille.
...肯定得叫露西尔
Rub it, baby. Clean that car.
擦掉 宝贝 清洁那辆车
Rub...rub...
擦... 擦...
She don't know what she's doing.
她不知道她在干什么
Oh boy, she knows exactly what she's doing.
哦 她清楚知道她在干什么
She's driving us crazy, and loving every minute of it!
她让我们发疯了!
Shut your mouth about my Lucille.
别说我的露西尔
Shut up, Babalugats.
闭嘴 芭芭鲁嘎次
You leave him alone? He's happy.
让他一个人? 他很高兴
Because he's a damn moron!
因为他是个该死的傻瓜!
Oh, man, that little Lucille.
哦 那个小露西尔
She was really a big lot of little gal, wasn't she?
她真是个丰满小女孩 不是吗?
Did you see how she was just about popping out of the top of that dress?
你没看到她几乎要把衣服撑破了?
Come on, Drag, cut it out.
托绳 别说了
And down below...
并且下面...
...man, that thing didn't reach no higher than...
...那东西没到...
She's liable to catch a cold running around like that.
她象那样到处跑很可能感冒的
It was stretched so tight across her bottom...
她的屁股那么紧...
...I do believe I saw one of those seams bust loose.
...我相信我看到过线给绷松过
And the opening got wider...
开口越开越大...
...and wider...and wider.
...越大...越大
Forget it, man.
忘了它吧 哥们
What do you mean, forget it?
你什么意思 忘了它吧?
Stop beating it into the ground. You ain't doing nobody no good.
别深入进去了 没对大家有什么好处
Okay, new-meat. You get some sleep.
好了 新来得 你睡觉吧
And save your strength, 'cause you're going to need it.
保存你的力气 因为你会需要的
Tomorrow.
明天
Why don't you just stay down, Luke?
你为什么不躺下 卢卡斯?
He's just going to knock you down again, buddy.
他会再扁你一通的 哥们
It's not your fault. He's just too big.
不是你的错 他太强壮了
Let him hit you in the nose and get some blood flowing.
让他打到你的鼻子流些血
Maybe the bosses'll stop it before he kills you.
可能老板们会在杀了你之前停下的
I don't want to frighten him.
我不想吓他
Stay down, Luke.
躺下 卢卡斯
Stay down, Luke. He's gonna kill you.
躺下 卢卡斯 他会杀了你的
Stay down!
躺下!
Somebody ought to stop this thing.
有人得让这停止
Stay down.
躺下
You're beat!
你被打败了!
You're going to have to kill me.
你得杀了我
All right, pass right. Here we go.
好了 递过去 我们走
King gets a three, queen deuce, seven pair of savannah's right here.
K得三点 Q两点 萨阿纳斯这里有7对
Deuce gets a four. No hell. Three gets a big ace.
两点拿个4 没门 3拿个大A
I call.
我叫
Kick a buck.
一块钱
A dollar?
一块钱?
One time.
一次
All right, I'll call.
好的 我叫
Hell, if I catch, I'm gonna burn you out. I call.
妈的 要是我抓了 我让你吃不了 我叫
King, three, he got a four. Queen, deuce gets a five.
K 3 他有个4 Q 两点的个五
Pair of seven gets a john.
一对7得个J
And the big ace gets...slop in the face.
一个A得个...满了
Okay, you still do the talking.
好了 还是你叫牌
Cuter again.
更好了
I call.
我叫
Kick a buck.
加一块钱
- What you got? - Pair of sevens.
- 你有什么? - 一对7
I can see that, mother-head. What have you got in the hole?
我能看到 傻帽 你到底有什么?
He ain't got nothing showing. Raze his head off.
他没什么牌 砍了他的头
He's been betting...
他一直在下注...
All right, why don't you call him.
好了 为什么你不叫他的牌呢
You've got to see it, Gambler.
你必须得看看 赌鬼
I can't. I can't catch a damn thing...
我不能 我什么都抓不住的...
I'm snake-bit. I fold.
我被蛇咬过 我埋牌
King, four, three. You got a nine. You got a nine. Nothing visible.
K 4 3 你有个9 你有个9 没什么可看的
Pair of sevens and a jack gets a six.
一对7和一个J是六
Savannahs, you still a better, man.
萨阿纳斯 你还是个赌家
Kick a buck.
加一块钱
Kick him back a buck!
跟他一块钱!
I'll see your buck and back a buck.
我要看你的牌并在加一块钱
Kick a buck.
一块钱
Damn!
妈的!
Don't look at me, mother-head.
别看我 傻帽
What're you going to do, play like a coconut? You got to call him.
你怎么办 象个傻瓜样的玩牌? 你得叫他的牌
I know he's got a pair of kings. You don't have to stuff'em up my nose.
我知道他有一对K 你不用指着我的鼻子
Well, you still got to call him, anyway.
唔 你还是得叫他的牌
The man's got kings. Get your tail out.
那个人有对K 滚开
You wanna see him? Right there.
你想看他的牌? 在这
Nothing. Handful of nothing.
什么都没有 一手的臭牌
You stupid mullet-head, he beat you with nothing.
你个愚蠢的傻帽 他什么都没有赢了你
Just like today when he kept coming back at me. With nothing.
就好像今天他老是来找我 什么都没有
Sometimes nothing can be a real cool hand.
有时候臭牌可以是一手很绝的牌
Move over.
走开
I'm going to sit in here next to my boy.
我打算坐在我哥们的旁边
Cool Hand Luke.
绝牌卢卡斯
Hey, Loudmouth!
喂 大嘴!
Come on, get up there. Your mama's waiting for you.
快来 上来这 你妈妈在等你
She never leaves me alone!
他从来不让我单独一个人!
Be glad you got somebody, kid.
很高兴你有人了 孩子
Luke, visitor for you.
卢卡斯 有人来看你
- Coming out here, Boss. - Come out, Luke.
- 这出来 老板 - 出来吧 卢卡斯
How did you find me?
你怎么找到我的?
That Helen...
那个海伦...
...she sent your things along with a note...
...她把你的东西连同一份信寄来...
...and then John here, he wrote to the police.
...琼那时候在那 他给警察写了信
Goin' around here, Boss?
这转一转 老板?
Well, Arletta, I've got to stay here.
唔 阿勒塔 我得呆在这
I always hoped to see you well-fixed...
我总是希望看到你安定下来...
...have me a crop of grandkids to fuss around with.
...给我养一堆孙子女来玩
I'd like to oblige you, Arletta, but...
我想逼你 阿勒塔 但是...
...right off, I just don't know where to put my hands on 'em.
...现在 我就是不怎么办好
You know, sometimes...
你知道 有时候...
...I wish people was like dogs, Luke.
...我希望人们象狗一样 卢卡斯
Comes a time, a day like when...
有一次 一天想当...
...the bitch just don't recognize the pups no more, so...
...那个母狗不再认识小狗们时 因此...
...she don't have no hopes, nor love to give her pain.
...她就没有希望了 也没有对她的痛苦的爱了
She just don't give a damn.
她就是什么也不管
They letting you smoke here?
他们让你抽烟吗?
Smoking it up here, Boss?
这抽烟了 老板?
You done your best, Arletta.
你已经尽全力了 阿勒塔
What I've done with myself is my own problem.
我自己做的是我自己的问题
Oh, no, it ain't, Luke. You ain't alone.
哦 不 不是的 卢卡斯 你不是一个人
Everywhere you go, I'm with you.
不管你到哪 我都和你在一起
And John, too.
还有琼
You never thought maybe that's a heavy load?
你从来没有想过那是个重档?
Why, we always thought you were strong enough to carry it.
为什么 我们一直以为你足够强壮来挑
Was we wrong?
我们错了吗?
I don't know.
我不知道
Well, things are just never the way...
唔 事情就是从来都不象...
...they seem, Arletta, you know that.
...它们看起来 阿勒塔 你知道的
A man's gotta go his own way.
一个男人得走他自己的路
Guess, I've just got to...
我想 我得...
...got to love you and let go.
...得爱你并让你去
I guess.
我想是的
I ain't asking what you're going to do when you get out because...
我不是问你出去后打算干什么因为...
...l'll be dead and it don't matter.
...我那时候就死了 也就不要紧了
You never did want to live forever.
你从来就没有想要永远活着
I mean, it wasn't such a hell of a life.
我意思是 人生也不是那么苦
I had me...some high old times.
我有过...一些老的快乐时光
Your old man, Luke...
你老头 卢卡斯...
...he wasn't much good for sticking around...
...他在的时候不是那么好...
...but, dammit, he made me laugh.
...但是 妈的 他让我笑
I would have liked to have known him, the way you talk about him.
我会希望了解他的 象你说的那样
He'd have broke you up.
他会让你伤心的
What went wrong?
怎么啦?
Nothing. Everything's cool as can be.
没什么 一切都很好
Arletta, I tried.
阿勒塔 我试过了
I mean to...
我想过...
...live always free and above board like you, but...
...像你样自由的 光明正大的生活 但是...
...I don't know, I just can't seem to find any elbow room.
...我不知道 我就是无法找到我的栖身之处
You always had good jobs.
你有过好的工作
And that girl in Kentucky.
和那个在肯塔基的女孩
Oh...l'd taken a shine to her.
哦... 我很喜欢她
She sure took off with that convertible fella.
她肯定和那个敞篷车的家伙跑了
Well, why not?
唔 为什么不呢?
Idea of marrying got you all, all bollixed up.
结婚的念头迷住你 全糊涂了
Trying to be respectable.
想要值得尊敬的
You was boring the hell out of all of us.
你让我们大家都厌烦了
I'm leaving the place to John.
我要走了去琼那里
That's good. He earned it.
很好 他应该的
Ain't nothing to do with it.
和这没什么关系
I just never gave John...
我就是从来没给过琼...
...the kind of, you know, feeling that I gave you.
...那种 你知道 我给你的那种感觉
So, I'm going to pay him back now.
因此 我要还给他
Don't feel you have to say anything.
你不必说什么
The way it is, you see...
事情是 你知道...
...sometimes you just have a feeling for a child...
...有时候你有种对小孩的感情...
...or else you don't.
...或你没有
With John, I just didn't.
对琼 我就没有
I gotta go, Arletta.
我得走了 阿勒塔
Laugh it up, kid. You, you'll make out.
笑一笑 孩子 你 你会出来的
Uncle Luke, why can't you have chains?
卢卡斯叔叔 为什么你没有锁链?
John-Boy, let me tell you something.
约翰孩子 让我告诉你
You know them chains ain't medals. You got them for making mistakes.
你要知道锁链不是奖章 你因为犯错误而得到它们
And you make a bad enough mistake, then you've got to deal with the Man.
当你犯了很大的错误的时候 你就得和那个人打交道
And he is one rough old boy.
他是个很凶的老家伙
So long, Arletta. Take care.
再见 阿勒塔 保重
You know it, kid.
你知道的 孩子
Now there ain't nothing to come back for.
现在没有什么要回来的
"Just a closer walk with Thee.
"就是和神靠的更近 "
"Grant it, Jesus, is my plea.
"如我愿 耶稣 是我的请求
"Daily walking close to Thee.
"每天和神走在一起
"Let it be, dear Lord...
"让他去吧 亲爱的上帝...
"...let it be.
"...让他去吧
"Through the days of toil that's near...
"通过辛苦的日子...
"...if I fall, dear Lord, who cares?
"...如果我跌到 亲爱的上帝 谁会在乎?
"Who but Thee...
"除了神有谁...
"...my burden shares?
"...分担我的重担?
"None but Thee...
"除了神没人...
"...dear Lord, none but Thee!"
"...亲爱的上帝 除了神没人! "
This gang's been doing so good...
这伙人干的很好...
...the Captain decided to give you something special.
...队长决定给你们些特殊的奖励
You've got yourselves a whole road of tarring to do.
你们要给以整条路铺上柏油
And I want to see you roll it.
我要看到你们开始
Pick up your shovels.
拿上你们的铲子
Get with it. Move!
去吧 走!
We're sure going to be walking the road today.
我们今天肯定能在这路上走了
What's the deal?
什么意思?
- Man, you think you been working hard? - This mother's going to break your back.
- 哥们 你以为干的很辛苦? - 这个混蛋要让你的腰折断
Let's move! Let's see those shovels!
干活! 让我看到那些铲子!
Going to twist my arm off if it don't kill me first. Right, Boss?
要把我的胳膊给拧下来了也别先杀我 对吗 老板?
Hey, buddy, slow down.
喂 哥们 慢下来
That's a long road.
那是条长路
Well, the man wants speed, let's just give it to him.
唔 那人要速度 让我们给他速度
Cram it in and break it out. Yeah. Go hard.
敲进去 敲出来 是的 努力
What are we racing for?
我们在竞赛什么?
Wants speed, let's give it to him.
要速度 让我们给他速度
Use that shovel like it was your spoon.
用这个铲子象用你的勺子
The man, boy, get the man!
那个人 孩子 抓住那个人!
Moving it up here, Boss.
走过来了 老板
Now you tell me, Rabbit, what's going on here?
告诉我 兔子 那是怎么回事?
I don't know, Boss. Think they're all bear-clawed.
我不知道 老板 我想他们都有熊掌
They don't know whether to smile, spit or swallow.
他们不知道是否该笑 吐口水还是吞
Well, they've never seen a bull gang before.
唔 他们从来没见过一队牛人
Where'd the road go?
这条路通到哪里?
That's it. That's the end of it.
就这了 这就是头
Man, there's still daylight.
哥们 还没天黑
About two hours left.
还有两个小时剩下
What do we do now?
我们该怎么办?
Nothing.
不干什么
Oh, Luke, you wild, beautiful thing!
哦 卢卡斯 你个漂亮的野小子!
You crazy handful of nothing!
你个疯狂的臭牌家伙!
"As Carol pressed her lips to him...
"当卡洛尔亲他的时候...
"...his right hand started a slow descent down her silken body.
"...他的右手开始慢慢的向下摸她光滑的身体
"Desire and fear, temptation and terror...
"渴望而又害怕 诱惑而又恐惧...
"...yearning and horror warred within her beautiful young body."
"...需求而又惧怕在她美丽的年轻的身体里斗争 "
Have to close those things, or we'd drown,
得结束那些东西了 不然我们会淹死的
but it's suffocating in here.
但这里让人窒息
Talk about drowning.
说到淹死
When I was in the navy...
当我还在海军的时候...
...I was on submarine duty once, and when you get down there...
...有一次我在潜艇上 当我们潜到那里...
Will you tell your story walkin'? It's too hot.
你能走着说你的故事吗? 太热了
Did you see my skinny little boy chow tonight?
你今晚看到我那个小个子中国人了吗?
He's matching you plate for plate.
他和你吃的一样多
I wasn't feeling good. I think I got an ulcer or something.
我不舒服 我想我得了溃疡或是什么
He had a bigger spoon. Make you look like yours had a hole in it.
他的勺子大些 让你的看起来像有个洞
Come on, Clarence.
快来 克拉伦斯
What do you mean, Clarence? You call me a liar?
你什么意思 克拉伦斯?你说我撒谎?
No, not a liar.
不 不是撒谎
You just have a common, likeable tendency toward exaggeration.
你就是有个通常的 很可能的趋向夸张
That there's the champion hog-gutter of this camp.
那是这个营的猪食冠军
Well, I've seen him eat ten chocolate bars...
唔 我见过他吃十个巧克力糖...
...and seven cold drinks in 15 minutes.
...和七杯饮料在15分钟内
He can eat busted bottles and rusty nails, any damn thing.
他能吃碎瓶子和锈钉子 任何东西
If you be so kind to let me cut off your Yankee head, he'll even eat that.
如果你能让我割了你的脑袋的话 他也能吃下去
I can eat 50 eggs.
我能吃50个鸡蛋
Nobody can eat 50 eggs.
没人能吃50个鸡蛋
You just said he could eat anything.
你刚说他什么都能吃
You ever eat 50 eggs?
你吃过50个鸡蛋?
Nobody ever eat 50 eggs.
没人吃过50个鸡蛋
Hey, Babalugats! We got a bet here.
喂 芭芭鲁嘎次! 我们打个赌
My boy says he can eat 50 eggs, he can eat 50 eggs.
他说他能吃50个鸡蛋 他能吃50个鸡蛋
Yeah, but in how long?
是的 但在多长时间内?
In an hour.
一个小时内
Well, I believe I'll take part in that wager.
唔 我相信我也参加这个赌局
Two dollars. Right here.
两块钱 在这
Come on now, let's talk some money.
来吧 让我们来谈谈钱的事
All right, $20. Anything.
好的 20美金 还有吗
The syndicate will cover any bet you want to make.
那个就可以让你赌任何注
Koko, get some paper.
芋头 拿点纸来
Drag, 50 eggs got to weigh a good six pounds.
托绳 50个鸡蛋得有六磅重
Man's gut can't hold that. They'll swell up and bust him open.
人的胃可装不了那么多 会撑起来胀破的
All right, get your money up. Now, Gambler, Dynamite, come on, get it up.
好了 拿你们的钱来 赌鬼 炸药 快点 起来
Koko-head's going to take all the money. Come on, Loudmouth, get it up.
芋头会拿着所有的钱 快点 大嘴 起来
Wait just a minute, now. How's he gonna eat them?
等一下 他怎么吃呢?
Boiled for 15 minutes. Eat the whole thing in an hour.
煮15分钟 在一个小时内全部吃下去
One rule. No throwing up.
一个条件 不准吐出来
He throws up, you forfeit everything.
他吐了 你们就全输了
Now when was the last time you ever saw my boy throw up?
你什么时候见过他吐?
Now shut your mouth and give your money to Koko.
闭上你的嘴把钱给芋头
Why did you have to say 50 for?
为什么你要说50呢?
Why couldn't you say 35 or 39.
为什么你不能说35或者39呢
It seemed a nice round number.
听起来是个不错的整数
That's money you're talking about. What's the matter with you?
你说的是钱 你有什么毛病?
Yeah, well, it'll be something to do.
是的 唔 有事做了
- Ten! - Ten, right!
- 十! - 十 对!
What did I do?
我做了什么?
I stole and I told lies.
我偷窃并说谎
But I loved my neighbor. And his wife.
但是我爱我的邻居 和他的老婆
He'll never make it.
他做不到的
What we've got to do is stretch that little old belly of yours.
我们得让你的腹部伸展
Get all this stuff out of the way.  Them eggs's coming down.
把所有的排出去 然后让蛋进去
We've got to get it all in fightingshape, like a barrage balloon.
我们得在战斗状态 象个诸塞气球
Ready...
准备好...
...and go!
...开始!
Hey, Boss, man needs a brown bomber and a dose of salts.
喂 老板 要点胡椒和盐
You can't do that!
你不能那样!
- I want my money back. - No money back.
- 我要拿回我的钱 - 不退钱
Twenty of those pills still won't make any difference.
20片那种药片也没什么区别
What are you worried about? He can't do it.
你担心什么? 他做不到的
What's he doing?
他在做什么?
All right, stand back, you pedestrians. This ain't no automobile accident.
好了 靠后 你们这些行人 这不是交通事故
That's all 50?
全部50?
Move over, losers. I got money riding here.
走开 输家 我马上就要赢钱了
All right, I've got it figured out.
好了 我想到了
If he eats an egg a minute, he's got ten minutes left to swallow them.
如果他一分钟吃一个蛋 他还有10分钟剩下
Hey, I just got five bucks from a rodeo outfit.
喂 我刚从牛仔服搞到5块钱
- Hey, you're peeling his eggs. - That's right, mister.
- 喂 你在剥他的蛋壳 - 是的 先生
He peels his eggs himself. That's understood.
他自己剥他的蛋 这是默认的
Now you may be just great at hanging paper around the big city...
你可能在大城市很懂搞文件...
...and passing bad checks...
...和用无效的支票...
...but us country boys ain't entirely brainless.
...但是我们乡下孩子也不是傻子
When it comes to the law, nothing is understood.
当说到法律时 没什么事默认的
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
等等! 等等!
Who made what law about peeling the eggs?
谁定的这个剥蛋的法律?
I'm his trainer. I'm the syndicate covering all bets.
我是他的教练 我来赌所有的赌注
And I'm his official egg-peeler. That's the law.
我是他法定的剥蛋人 这就是法律
Just wait till the hour starts, that's all.
等到这个小时开始 就这样
I was banking on the fact he had to peel 'em.
我赌的时候就是想着他得剥它们
What's going on?
怎么啦?
You ready, Champ?
你准备好了 冠军?
Ready?
准备好了?
Go!
开始!
Two...
二...
...three...
...三...
Man, he's going to lose a finger eating eggs like that.
像他那样吃蛋得吃掉个手指
Twenty-four...
二十四...
...twenty-five...
...二十五...
Slow down a little.
慢一点
Twenty-six...
二十六...
Forget it, he's wasting time.
算了吧 他在浪费时间
Thirty-two.
三十二
Just have 18 more to go...
还有十八个...
What's wrong?
怎么啦?
- I think he's gonna throw up! - Oh, no.
- 我想他要吐了 - 哦 不
- That's it. He's finished. - C'mon Luke!
- 就这样了 他完了 - 加油 卢卡斯
Eighteen to go.
还有十八个
He's finished.
他完了
Just like a ripe watermelon that's about to bust itself open.
象个熟透了的西瓜就要爆了样
Your boy's done for, Drag. I'm putting in my last tenner.
托绳 你们都好了 我再加我最后10块钱
- it don't look good, Drag. - Man's gut can't hold more than that.
- 托绳 看起来不妙 - 人的胃装不下那么多
- He's all right, he's all right. - He's going to make it.
- 他没事 他没事 - 他能做到的
I give you a dollar he don't eat all 50 eggs, I get two dollars back.
我给你一块钱 他没吃完所有的50个蛋 我要拿回来2块钱
Fixer, you're a sweet old boy.
固定器 你真是个好人
Better take that dollar and buy yourself a new spark plug or something.
最好拿那块钱给你自己买个新的火花塞还是什么的
But as long as you done took a stand...
但是只要你下了注...
...why don't you put some money where your mouth is and not no measly buck!
...为什么你不下点钱你嘴巴说的而不是一块钱!
Well, all I got is 3.75, Drag.
唔 我只有3 75 托绳
That's a bet, Koko.
是个注了 芋头
All right, now the rest of you, I want to hear from some big-money men.
好了 你们其余的 我想听到你们那些有钱人
Where's all the high rollers?
赌大钱的人都去哪了?
I believe you've got it all, Dragline. Every cent in the camp is riding.
我相信所有的钱都在这了 托绳
- What's the time? - Come on, baby.
- 时间呢? - 快点 宝贝
Twenty-four minutes to go.
还有24分钟
Just let that little old belly sag and enjoy itself.
让那个腹部下垂并享受
Forty-one.
四十一
Stay loose, buddy. Just nine more between you and everlasting glory.
放松 哥们 你离永远的荣耀就只有9个了
- Is he eating them, Alibi? - He's chewing. Look at that.
- 他在吃吗 阿拉比? - 他在嚼 看看那
They're pigeon eggs, that's all. Fish eggs, practically.
那是鸽子蛋 实际上是鱼蛋
How much more time, Carr?
还有多长时间 卡尔?
Six minutes to go, Stevie.
还有六分钟 斯蒂夫
Chew, chew, chew!
嚼 嚼 嚼!
You're helpin' him chew now!
你在帮他嚼!
Oh, no.
哦 不
Forty-two.
四十二
Tiny, tiny egg.
很小 很小的蛋
Two minutes to time!
还有两分钟!
Forty-four.
四十四
All right, now, get mad at them damned eggs.
好了 对那些该死的蛋发疯吧
Eat it there, boy.
快吃
Chew on it.
嚼呀!
Gnaw on it.
嚼呀
Thirty seconds.
三十秒
You got the last one.
你还有最后一个
Stuff it down in there. Get it in.
吞下去
That's the last one in there now, baby. Chew. Chew.
最后一个了 宝贝 嚼 嚼
Ten...nine...eight...
十...九...八...
...seven...six...five...
...七...六...五...
...four...three...two...
...四...三...二...
...one...zero!
...一...零!
Hold it! He didn't swallow the last.
等一下! 他没吞下最后一个
You think so? Just take a look here.
你那么认为? 看看这
Open that mouth.
张嘴
Nobody can eat 50 eggs.
没人能吃五十个蛋
Snake in the grass here, Boss!
这是草丛里的蛇 老板!
Get it.
明白了
Get it!
明白了!
Hey, Boss.
喂 老板
Forgot your walking stick?
忘记你的巡视棍了?
Man, you sure can shoot.
哥们 你可真能吃
You gone too far when you mess with the Man With No Eyes.
你搞没眼力的人搞得太过火了
You'll be out of here in a little bit.
你得在这里呆一会
Why don't you take it a little easy?
你为什么不收敛一点呢?
All right, everybody in the trucks.
好了 卡车上的人
Boy, look at Him go! Bam! Bam!
看着他走! 骗 骗!
Just knock it off, Luke! You can't talk about Him that way.
别闹 卢卡斯! 你不能那么说他
You still believe in that big bearded Boss up there?
你还相信那个大胡子老板?
You think He's watching us?
你认为他在监视我们?
Get in here!
到这来!
Ain't you scared?
你不害怕吗?
Ain't you scared of dying?
你不害怕死亡吗?
Dying? Boy, He can have this little life anytime He wants to.
死亡? 他随时都可以要这条小命
You hear that? You hear it?
你听到了? 你听到了?
Come on! You're welcome to it, Old Timer.
欢迎你来 老家伙
Let me know You're up there. Come on.
让我知道你在那里
Love me, hate me, kill me, anything. Just let me know it.
爱我 恨我 杀了我 随便 就是告诉我
Just standing in the rain...
站在雨中...
...talking to myself.
...自言自语
Blind Dick is paying back three and borrowing five.
瞎棍还3块借5块
Next.
下一个
You borrowing or paying back?
你是借还是还?
Borrowing.
借
Well, Mr. Cool Hand here is the soft heart in our loan department.
唔 臭牌先生是我们贷款部的好好先生
I just need five, Luke.
我只需要5块 卢卡斯
I knew you could really eat all them eggs.
我知道你能吃掉那些蛋
Yeah, well, I didn't.
是的 唔 我没有
That's my darling Luke. He grins like a baby...
那是我亲爱的卢卡斯 他笑得像个孩子...
...but he bites like a 'gator.
...但是他咬起来像只鳄鱼
I believe I still owe you thirty.
我相信我还欠你30
I don't suppose you'd care to take a check?
我想你不介意收支票吧?
For you.
为了你
His mother's dead.
他母亲死了
"I don't care if it rains or freezes...
"我不在乎下雨还是结冰...
"...as long as I got my plastic Jesus...
"...只要我得到我的塑料耶稣...
"...sitting on the dashboard of my car.
"...放在我的车上
"Comes in colors pink and pleasant.
"有着愉快地粉红的颜色
"Glows in the dark 'cause it's iridescent.
"在黑暗中闪光"因为这是彩虹色的
"Take it with you...
"随身带着...
"...when you travel far.
"...当你出远门的时候
"Get yourself a sweet Madonna...
"戴上玛丽亚...
"...dressed in rhinestone sittin' on...
"...穿着水晶的坐在...
"...a pedestal of abalone shell.
"...贝壳的基座上
"Going 90, I ain't scary...
"快90了 我没有害怕...
"...'cause I got the Virgin Mary...
"...因为我有圣母玛丽亚...
"...assuring me...
"...在保佑我...
"...that I won't go to hell.
"...我不会去地狱
"Get yourself a sweet Madonna...
"戴上玛丽亚...
"...dressed in rhinestone sittin' on...
"...穿着水晶的坐在...
"...pedestal of abalone shell.
"...贝壳的基座上
"Going 90, I ain't scary...
"快90了 我没有害怕...
"...'cause I got the Virgin Mary. assuring me...
"...'因为我有圣母玛丽亚 在保佑我...
"...that I won't go to hell."
"...我不会去地狱 "
Luke, fall out.
卢卡斯 离队
When a man's mother dies and...
当一个人的母亲死了...
...he gets to thinkin' about her funeral and paying respects...
...他得想想她的葬礼和守灵...
...before he knows it, his mind ain't right.
...在他知道之前 他的头脑就不对劲
He's got rabbit in his blood and he runs.
他有兔子的血缘 他就跑了
We're keeping you off the road for a while.
我们会让你有一段时间不再到路上做事
I'm going to say a prayer for your ma, Luke.
我会为你的母亲祈祷的 卢卡斯
Sorry, Luke, I'm just doing my job. You've got to appreciate that.
对不起 卢卡斯 我只是在做我的工作 你得明白
Calling it your job don't make it right, Boss.
叫这为你的工作也不意味着这是正确的 老板
Ma's in the ground now, God rest her soul.
母亲入土了 愿她安息
You best forget about it, Luke.
你最好忘了它 卢卡斯
Got a day and a half lay-in. Tomorrow's a holiday.
有一天半休息 明天是假日
- Happy Fourth of July! - Same to you!
- 国庆节快乐! - 你也是!
Break it up. Come on, you've had your fun.
别这样 快来 高兴一下
First bell! Move it, Stevie.
第一道铃! 快走 斯蒂夫
What have you got, another one of them dirty books?
你搞得什么 又一本下流小说?
Do yourself a favor. Read this part that Koko underlined for me.
你来吧 读芋头下划线的那部分
"She moved her head another inchwhile he reached up...
"当他伸手时 她的头又移了一寸...
"...and put his left hand on Carol's...
"...把他的左手放在卡洛尔的...
"...as Carol pressed her..."
"...当卡洛尔把她的压向..."
Oh, I can't stand it!
哦 我无法忍受了!
You're just coming to the interesting part now.
你就要到有趣的部分了
- I can't hear you. - "Her trembling body..."
- 我听不见你 - "她颤栗的身体..."
Last bell. Last bell.
最后一道铃 最后一道铃
Move it.
快点
What's that noise outside?
外面是什么声音?
Man on the fence, Boss!
有人在围墙上 老板!
Wait a minute, damn it!
等一下 妈的!
Come back here! Dammit!
回来! 妈的!
Forty-eight, Boss. One in the box and one in the bush.
48个 老板 一个在黑屋子和一个在草丛里
Forty-eight. One in the box and one in the bush.
48个 一个在黑屋子和一个在草丛里
Oh, listen to Blue sing!
哦 听爵士演唱!
He's on to him, he says. He's got him.
他说 他抓到他了 他抓到他了
Hell, that dog's running around in circles.
妈的 那条狗在绕圈子跑
No, he's on to him.
不 他抓到他了
Captain says for us to wait till the patrol gets here.
队长告诉我们等到巡逻的来
Shoulda waited for me to get him out.
该等我一起把他提出来的
Loose like that he can run him crazy.
象那么松会让他发疯的
Didn't even have enough sense to run from the road like everybody else.
甚至不不知道象别人一样从路上跑的
Oh, I'm beat. This ain't my job nohow.
哦 我输了 这绝对不是我的事了
Your dogs are crazy.
你的狗发疯了
He's smarter than a dog. Let's go!
他比狗还狡猾 我们走!
He made it!
他成功了!
Look, Captain!
看 队长!
Look what he done to Blue.
看他对爵士做了什么
He's dead.
他死了
He run himself plumb to death.
他自己跑摔死的
Get in line facing the Captain.
回去见队长
You're going to get used to wearing them chains after a while, Luke...
卢卡斯 过一段时间你会习惯戴锁链的...
...but you never stop listening to them clinking.
...但是你要不时地听它们叮当响
'Cause they're going to remind you of what I've been saying...
因为他们会提醒你我说过什么...
...for your own good.
...为了你自己
Wish you'd stop being so good to me, Captain.
希望你不要对我那么好了 队长
Don't you ever talk that way to me.
不许以那种方式和我说话
Never!
绝对不许!
What we've got here is...
我们这的问题是...
...failure to communicate.
...交流失败
Some men you just can't reach.
你不知道有些人
So you get what we had here last week. Which is the way he wants it.
因此你上个星期得到这些 这是他想要的
Well, he gets it.
嗯 那他得到了
I don't like it any more than you men.
我比你们更讨厌这
Well, lookie here.
嗯 看看这
I knew they'd get you.
我知道他们会抓到你的
Them chains and a bonus of a couple of years...
锁链和加几年的奖励...
Your running days are over forever, boy.
你跑路的日子永远结束了
Hell, I'd like to see you try to run again.
妈的 我希望你再看到逃跑
You know, you getting so you smell so bad I can track you myself.
你知道 你身上那么大的味我自己都能找到你
Yeah, well, that ought to be easy for a genuine son of a bitch.
是的 嗯 那对个混蛋天才来说应该是很容易的
What happened. How far did you get?
怎么了 你跑了多远?
Shut up and let him eat.
闭嘴 让他吃东西
About a mile and a half.
大概有一里半
This supermarket parking lot.
在那个超市的停车场
Found a car with keys in the ignition.
找到有一辆车上有钥匙
Hit this red light and this police car slides up alongside.
碰到红灯 这辆警车就开上来了
Then what did you do?
那你怎么办?
Waited for that light to change.
等那个红灯变
This cop kept looking over, wondering what somebody looks like me...
那个警察老是看过来 在想有谁象我...
...dressed in state issue, was doin' driving a shiny new buggy.
...穿着监狱服 开着崭新的车
So what did you do?
那你怎么办?
He leaned over and said, "Hey!"
他斜过来说 "喂! "
Top flight police work, that's all there is to it.
超过了警察该做的 就这样了
Fella's probably a lieutenant by now.
那个家伙很可能升中尉了
Now, we're just gonna lay low and build time.
现在 我们得低调等待时机
Before you know it, the heat's going to be off of you.
在你知道之前 你就不热了
Everything will be right back where it was. Right, sweet buddy?
一切都恢复正常了 对吗 哥们?
I hear tell you don't believe in no God, Luke.
我听说你不信上帝 卢卡斯
I was wondering how come a nice, clean-cut young fellow like you...
我在想怎么象你这样一个干净温和的年轻人...
...gets put on the hard road.
...会走上这条路
Now I reckon I knows.
现在我猜我知道了
I've been on the road gang almost 22 years.
我在这有几乎22年了
In all that time, I ain't never killed a white man...
在那些时间里 我从来没有杀过一个白人...
...but I ain't afraid to because...
...但是我也不是害怕因为...
Excuse me, Boss, don't mean to interrupt. Caught short here.
对不起 老板 不是有意打断 尿急了
So did I. It's okay.
我也是 没事
You just go on out there behind them trees.
你出去到那些树后面
Man's gotta have his privacy sometime.
男人有时候得有些私人空间
You just keep shaking that bush so we know you're there.
你一直摇那些灌木这样我们知道你在那里
Just keep shaking that bush.
一直摇那些灌木
Shaking it up here, Boss!
摇了 老板!
Still shaking it, Boss.
还在摇 老板
I'm shaking it, Boss.
我在摇 老板
He's gone. Get the dogs.
他跑了 带上狗
What you got them on for?
你拿那些干什么?
How do you take your pants off?
你怎么脱你的裤子的?
Best way is to get rid of them leg irons...
最好是去掉那些脚链...
...but you ain't strong enough.
...但是你没有那么壮
Strong enough for what?
那么壮干什么?
Hell, you couldn't heft an axe.
妈的 你不能劈斧头
Can, too.
能
- I bet you can't. - Can, too.
- 我打赌你不能 - 能
Bet you can't.
打赌你不能
Well, then, go get it, man.
嗯 那么去拿来
What's your name, boy?
你叫什么名字 孩子?
Aren't you going to take those stripes off your pants?
你不打算把你裤子上那些带子扯掉?
You know it, kid.
你明白的 孩子
- You want to see something real funny? - Yeah?
- 你想看有趣的事吗? - 是的?
Well, you go on in there and you get me...
嗯 你到里面去拿些...
...chili powder and pepper and the like.
...辣椒粉和辣椒之类的
You better let me handle that, son.
你最好让我来拿 孩子
Here they are.
给你
Thank you, son.
谢谢你 孩子
What's the matter with him?
他怎么啦?
He'll be all right.
他没事
Now listen. You're going to have some fun. You hear that?
现在听着 你们要好好玩一下 你们听到了吗?
Well, you remember how them dogs do when they come through here...
你记住那些狗到这里后怎么样了...
...so you can tell me about it someday, okay?
...以后你可以告诉我 好吗?
My wife hasn't written me for a month.
我老婆有一个月没给我写信了
She's probably sick of you.
她很可能讨厌你了
Magazine for you.
你的杂志
Hey, Koko, who's sending me magazines?
喂 芋头 谁给我送杂志?
Don't know. It's from Atlanta.
不知道 是从亚特兰大来的
My uncle!
我叔叔!
Ain't heard from him in eight years and now he's sending me magazines!
有八年没他的消息了现在他给我寄杂志!
He must have gone crazy!
他一定是疯了!
Look at that!
看看那!
- That's Luke? - Look at that, two of 'em.
- 是卢卡斯? - 看看那 他们两个
What's the writing say?
写了些什么?
What's that, that writing say?
那是什么 写的什么?
"Dear Boys: Playing it cool."
"亲爱的哥们：要乖 "
They must be six feet tall.
他们有六尺高
Look at that!
看那个!
My baby! We're in here digging and dying...
我的宝贝! 我们在这里挖和等死...
...he's out there living and flying.
...他在外面享受和自由自在
Koko, will you stop that?
芋头 别说了好不好?
Why don't you try making me?
为什么你不让我呢?
- Hey, Drag? Let me see the picture. - What for?
- 喂 托绳? 给我看看照片 - 干什么?
Come on, Drag, let us see the picture.
来吧 托绳 让我们看看照片
No, you're just a kid. What you know about it?
不 你还是个孩子 你知道什么?
You don't want to see that dirty picture.
你不能看那个下流照片
Luke and those broads and all that booze.
卢卡斯还有裸露以及酗酒
Come on, let me take a look.
来吧 给我看看
It would go to your coconut head. You're liable to get ideas...
这会进入你的死脑筋的 你很容易会有想法...
...and pass right out.
...然后就去试
Now, what you figure it's worth? A peek at that there picture?
现在你认为值得吗? 看一眼那照片?
A quick look now. I'm not talking about no memorizing job.
就瞄一眼 我不会记住的
Cold drink.
饮料
A coke? One cold drink...
一杯可乐? 一杯冷饮...
...to feast your starving, fishy, little eyes on the picture?
...来满足你的饥渴 小鱼儿 瞟一眼照片?
A true vision of paradise itself...
天堂的真实写照...
...with two of the angels right there frisking around with my boy?
...有两个天使在那站在我的哥们的身边?
Okay, it's a deal.
好的 成交
One cold drink, in advance.
一杯冷饮 预付
One chilly bottle right in my hot little hand.
一个冰冷的瓶子在我火热的小手里
That goes for the rest of you mother-heads, too.
你们其余的也一样
Let me see.
让我看
Did you pay?
你付钱了吗?
Come on in there, Wicker Man.
到这来 瘦条
You run one time, you got yourself a set o' chains.
你跑一次 你就得到一条锁链
You run twice, you get yourself two sets.
你跑两次 你就有两条了
You ain't going to need no third set...
你不需要第三条的...
...because you're going to get your mind right.
...因为你的想法就会改正
And I mean "right."
我意思是说"正确"
Take a good look at Luke.
好好看看卢卡斯
Cool Hand Luke.
臭牌卢卡斯
Easy, easy! Let him breathe!
放松 放松! 让他呼吸!
Oh my poor baby. They done you real good.
哦 我可怜的宝贝 他们让你够受
I don't know if you're going to have the girls chasing you.
我不知道你是否会让这些女孩追你
I'll get some aspirin.
我要来些阿司匹林
He should have a doctor.
他应该有个医生
Ain't you gonna learn?
你还没有明白吗?
They ain't gonna let no doctor see what they done.
他们不会让医生看到他们做的事
Get your razor. We'll clean up some them cuts on his head.
拿你的刀片来 我们来整理他头上的伤口
How you feeling, buddy? How you feeling?
你怎么样 哥们? 你感觉怎么样?
Somebody ought to give him something cold to drink.
有人得给他点冷饮
- That's my baby. - Now he's going to be all right.
- 那是我的宝贝 - 现在他没事了
Hey, Luke, look we got the picture you sent us. Look here.
喂 卢卡斯 看我们收到你寄给我们的照片了 看这
You really can pick 'em, Luke.
你真能挑呀 卢卡斯
Come on...tell us. What were they like?
快点...告诉我们 他们怎么样?
Can't you wait until he stops bleeding?
你不能等到他止血了?
- Why don't ya go back to your knitting? - Oh, knock it off, you guys.
- 为什么你不回去织你的毛衣? - 别这样
Picture's a phoney. Cost me a week's pay.
照片是假的 花了我一个星期来付
What do you mean, a phoney?
你什么意思 假的?
What you talking about, man?
你在说什么 哥们?
We saw them two women right here in the picture.
我们看到这两个女人在这照片上
Did you have them both at once? I mean, together?
你同时和她们俩? 我意思是 一起?
Picture's a phoney. I had it made up for you guys.
照片是假的 我为你们做的
What do you mean? We saw it all!
你什么意思? 我们都看到了
You was having a big time, man.
你在享受呢 哥们
You had it made!
你造的!
Nothing. Made nothing, had nothing.
一无所有 什么都没做 什么都没有
Couple of towns, couple of bosses.
几个镇 几个老板
I laughed out loud once, he turned me in.
我大笑过一次 他就把我抓了
But I got it here!
但是我这有!
Oh, come on! Stop beating it!
哦 来吧! 别说了!
Get out there yourself!
自己出来吧!
Stop feeding off me! Get outa here!
别喂我了! 出去!
Can't breathe. Give me some air!
不能呼吸了 给我点空气!
Well, he ain't himself, can't you see that?
嗯 他不是他自己了 你没明白吗?
He's all beat up. He don't know what he's sayin'.
他被打坏了 他不知道他在说什么
All right, come on, break it up.
好了 别说了
Now, straighten out that bench.
现在 把那里收拾好
You were eyeballing.
你在盯
Can't get your mind on them weeds if you're eyeballing.
为什么你不能盯那些草呢
You don't need reasons to kick me, Boss.
你不需要理由来踢我 老板
First bell. Move it.
第一道铃 快点
He'll never make it.
他永远不会成功的
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
That old box will collapse and fall apart before old Luke calls it quits.
那个老黑屋子会在卢卡斯放弃之前倒塌的
Your Luke's got more guts than brains.
你的卢卡斯有勇无谋
Well, I don't see no sign of guts in you.
嗯 我看你连勇气都没有
No. No chains, either.
不 也没有锁链
Big deal paperhanger, passing two bit checks.
糊纸盒子的 把那两个递过来
You haven't had much luck playing follow-the-leader, have you?
你跟着领导走的不是很顺利 对吗?
You want to spend the night in the box, too?
你也想关一晚上黑屋子?
Well, here's our champion hog-gut. Hasn't eaten for four days.
嗯 这是我们猪食冠军 有四天没吃东西了
You're going to need a little extra. Got plenty for you.
你会要多吃一点 这有很多了
Now you know the rules.
现在你明白规矩了
Got to clean your plate or go back to the box. Right, Boss?
洗干净盘子或者回黑屋子里 对吗 老板?
That's enough, Dogboy.
好了 狗娃
Oh, man used to free-world food has got a big appetite.
哦 习惯于自由世界食物的人胃口很好呀
We're going to stretch that hog-belly right out?
我们打算扩展那个猪胃吗?
Well, you made the week, boy.
嗯 你做这星期
Now you got a day and a half to rest up for old Monday.
现在你有一天半来休息准备老样子星期一
That ditch is Boss Kean's ditch.
那条沟是克英老板的沟
I told him that dirt in it is your dirt.
我告诉他沟里的土是你的土
What's your dirt doing in his ditch?
你的土在他的沟里干什么?
I don't know, Boss.
我不知道 老板
You better get in there and get it out, boy.
你最好下去挖出来
"We work in the morning hear the ding-dong ring...
"我们早上工作 听到丁冬的铃声...
"...go march to the table, see the same damn thing.
"...排队到桌子 看到可恶的东西
"Well, it's on the table, a knife, a fork and a pan.
"嗯 在桌子上 一把刀 叉 和盘子
"Say anything about it you get in trouble with the man.
"随便说什么你都得有麻烦
"That Midnight Special. Shine a light on me.
"那个特殊的午夜 光照到我
"Let the Midnight Special shine your ever-loving light on me.
"让那特殊的午夜将你爱之光照到我
"If you ever go to Houston, boy, you better walk right.
"如果你要到休斯敦 你最好走好
"And you better not stagger, and you better not fight...
"你最好别摇摇摆摆 你最好别打架...
"...Because the sheriff will arrest you."
"...因为警长会逮捕你 "
Luke, what you think you're doing?
卢卡斯 你以为你在做什么?
Just getting my dirt out of Boss Kean's ditch, Boss.
在把我的土挖出克英老板的沟 老板
I'm damned if you're going to put your dirt in my yard.
你要是胆敢把你的土放到我的院子里
You hear me?
你听到了吗?
Now let's get it out of here.
让我们把这搞出去
I told you to get your dirt out of Boss Kean's ditch, didn't I?
我告诉你把你的土挖出克英老板的沟里 不是吗?
Yeah, Boss.
是的 老板
Then how come it ain't out?
那么怎么没有呢?
I don't know, Boss.
我不知道 老板
You don't know.
你不知道
"Ain't no grave going to keep my body down.
"没有坟墓能让我的身体倒下
"Ain't no grave...
"没有坟墓能...
"...going to hold my body down.
"...让我的身体躺下
"Keep Your mind on me above.
"看顾我的心
"Keep Your heart full of love.
"留守你的爱心
"Ain't no grave gonna hold my body down..."
"没有坟墓能让我的身体倒下..."
What's all this dirt doing in here?
这些土在这里是怎么回事?
I don't know...
我不知道...
"When I was a little bitty baby, my mamma used to rock me in my cradle.
"当我还是个小婴儿的时候 我母亲总是用摇床来摇我
"In them old cotton fields back home."
"在家乡那些老的棉花地里 "
Don't, Boss.
不要 老板
Get to work.
去工作
Don't, Boss. Don't hit me anymore.
不要 老板 别再打我了
For God's sake, don't hit me anymore.
看在上帝的分上 别再打我了
What was that you said? What was that name you used, Luke?
你说什么? 你说看在谁的分上 卢卡斯?
Oh, God!
哦 上帝!
Oh, God, I pray to God you don't hit me anymore.
哦 上帝 我向上帝祷告 你不要再打我了
I'll do anything you say, but I can't take anymore.
你说什么我就做什么 但是我再不能忍受了
- You got your mind right, Luke? - Yeah...
- 你这样想是对的 卢卡斯? - 是的...
...mind right.
...正确想法
Oh, I got it right, Boss.
哦 我想通了 老板
Suppose you was to backslide on us?
要是你欺骗我们?
Oh, no, I won't, Boss.
哦 不 我不会 老板
Suppose you was to back-sass?
要是你顶嘴?
Oh, no, I won't. I won't. I got my mind right.
哦 不 我不会了 我不会了 我想通了
You try to run again, we're going to kill you.
你要是再试着逃跑 我们会杀了你
I won't, I won't, Boss.
我不会了 我不会了 老板
Go get cleaned up and get yourself some sleep. Expect you need it.
去洗吧然后去睡觉 想来你也需要
Come on, son.
去吧 孩子
Come on up outa there.
上来吧
I got my mind right.
我想通了
Where are you?
你在哪里?
Where are you now?
- All right. Smoke it up. - Yes, sir.
- 好了 抽烟 - 好的 先生
Luke, water 'em down.
卢卡斯 给他们水
Yes, Boss.
是 老板
Luke! Fetch the rifle.
卢卡斯! 拿枪来
You got him, Boss. You got him.
你抓到他了 老板 你抓到他了
Go fetch it, Luke.
去拿来 卢卡斯
There he is, Boss. Deader than hell, but won't let go.
他在那 老板 死定了 但是不会让他走
You cut that up for our lunch, Luke.
你割来做我们的午餐 卢卡斯
Yes, Boss Paul.
是 保罗老板
He took the keys off of Dogboy's truck.
他拿走了狗娃卡车的钥匙
He got the keys here, too.
他这有钥匙
"I'm shaking it here, Boss. I'm shaking it."
"我在摇 老板 我在摇 "
That's my baby, Luke.
那是我的好孩子 卢卡斯
"Don't hit me, Boss. Only don't hit me.
"别打我 老板 就是别打我
"I'll do whatever you say."
"你说什么我就做什么 "
You are an original, that's what you are.
你是你原本的你
Those mullet-heads didn't even know you were fooling.
那些傻帽们不知道你在愚弄他们
Fooling them? You can't fool them about something like that.
愚弄他们? 你不能象那样愚弄他们
They broke me.
他们击垮了我
But they didn't get my mind right. Not with no sticks. No, sir.
但是他们没有让我想通 不时用棍子 不 先生
All that time you were planning on running again.
这些时间你都在计划再次逃跑
Never planned anything in my life.
一生中从来没有计划过任何事
That's just a little old farm road. Clean as a whistle.
那只是条老乡村路
I worked it a couple times. We're home free. Come on.
我在那做过几次 我自由回家 来吧
We ain't going nowhere.
我们哪都不去
Now, what are you talking about, Luke?
现在 你在想些什么 卢卡斯?
We're going by my house and we're going to have a big meal.
我们到我家去大吃一顿
Then I'm going to show you a couple of farm girls that really know what fun...
然后我介绍几个很懂怎么玩的女孩...
And then we're going to get Koko out of there.
然后我们把芋头搞出去
And then the terrible trio is gonna be complete again.
然后那可怕的三驾马车就全了
Man, this old free world ain't going to know which ear to stand on.
这个老自由世界会有多么好
Yeah, well, you and Koko can handle it without me.
是的 嗯 你和芋头不用我也能搞好
What's you mean, Luke?
你什么意思 卢卡斯?
I done enough world-shaking for a while.
我搞够了
You do the rest of it for me. Send me a postcard about it.
你来完成剩下的 给我寄张明信片
- But Luke... - Take it easy, Drag.
- 但是卢卡斯... - 别激动 托绳
Where are you going?
你去哪里?
Just on my own.
我自己一个人
But what am I going to do all by myself?
但是我打算一个人去吗?
Man, if I hadn't lost my head. I only had a couple of years to do.
如果我没记错 我只有几年来做了
But when I saw you tearing down the road in that truck...
但是当我在那辆卡车里看到你整路...
Well, you're right, Luke.
嗯 你是对的 卢卡斯
We ought to split up.
我们得分开
And then, and then it will be safer for the both of us.
然后 我们都会更安全
Just the same, you're a good old boy, Luke.
同时 你是个好人 卢卡斯
You take care!
保重!
Anybody here?
还有人吗?
Hey, Old Man. You home tonight?
喂 老头 你今晚回家?
Can You spare a minute. It's about time we had a little talk.
你有时间吗 是时候我们谈谈了
I know I'm a pretty evil fellow...
我知道我是个很坏的家伙...
...killed people in the war and got drunk...
...在战争中杀人和酗酒...
...and chewed up municipal property and the like.
...和破坏政府财产之类的
I know I got no call to ask for much...
我知道我没什么来要求许多...
...but even so, You've got to admit You ain't dealt me no cards in a long time.
...但是即使是这样 你得承认你有很长时间不用烦我了
It's beginning to look like You got things fixed so I can't never win out.
开始看起来像你定下了些事那样我永远出不去
Inside, outside, all of them...
内在 外在 所有的...
...rules and regulations and bosses.
...规矩 条款 和老板们
You made me like I am.
你使我喜欢我现在的自己
Now just where am I supposed to fit in?
现在我该到哪里去?
Old Man, I gotta tell You.
老头 我得告诉你
I started out pretty strong and fast.
我开始很强壮并且很快
But it's beginning to get to me.
但是这也让我想到
When does it end?
什么时候结束?
What do You got in mind for me?
你想到了什么?
What do I do now?
我现在该怎么办?
On my knees, asking.
跪下了 问
Yeah, that's what I thought.
是的 那是我想的
I guess I'm pretty tough to deal with?
我想我很难对付的?
A hard case.
困难的
Guess I gotta find my own way.
我想我得找到自己的路
Is that Your answer, Old Man?
那是你的答案 老头?
I guess You're a hard case, too.
我想你也是个困难户
Luke, you all right?
卢卡斯 你还好吧?
They got us, boy. They're out there, thicker than flies.
他们抓到了我们 他们在那 比苍蝇还多
Bosses, dogs, sheriffs...
老板们 狗 还有警长们...
...more guns than I've ever seen in my life. You ain't got a chance.
...比我一辈子见过的枪还多 你根本没机会
They caught up with me right after we split up.
我们一分手他们就抓到了我
And they were aiming to kill you. But I fixed that.
他们本来要杀了你 但是我阻止了他们
I got them to promise if you give up peaceful...
我让他们保证如果你投降...
...they ain't even going to whip you this time.
...他们甚至都不会抽打你这次
They even going to give us our same bunks back?
他们还是给我们原来的床?
Sure, why not?
当然 为什么不呢?
We only been gone a couple of hours. They're reasonable men.
我们只跑了几个小时 他们是讲理的人
You've got to listen to me.
你们得听我的
All you've got to do is give up...
你们要做的就是放弃...
...nice and quiet.
...安静而友好的
Just play it cool.
就是要乖
Yeah, like I always do?
是的 象我一直以来?
Yeah, just play it...
是的 就是要...
"What we got here is a failure to communicate."
"我们到这是交流失败 "
Go get him.
去抓他
You hang on in there, Luke. You hang on.
你停在那里 卢卡斯 你别动
There's going to be some world-shaking, Luke.
会有震惊世界的 卢卡斯
We're going to send you a postcard.
我们会给你发明信片的
You follow me and I'll radio the emergency clinic to open up.
你跟着我 我会叫急症所开门
I'm taking him to the prison hospital.
我带他去监狱医院
But that's an hour away. He isn't going to make it.
但那有一小时路远 他快不行了
Get out of the way. He's ours.
走开 他是我们的
They took him right down that road.
他们带他去那条路了
- What'd he look like, Drag? - Yeah, Drag.
- 他看起来怎么样 托绳? - 是的 托绳
Did he have his eyes open or closed?
他的眼睛是睁着还是闭着?
- He was smiling. - Smiling?!
- 他在笑 - 笑?!
That's right. You know...
对 你知道...
...that...Luke smile of his?
...那... 卢卡斯他的笑?
He had it on his face right to the very end.
他的脸上有着笑容
Hell, if they didn't know it 'fore...
妈的 如果他们以前不知道这...
...they could tell right then that they weren't ever going to beat him.
...他们可以看出的话他们就不会打他了
That old Luke smile.
卢卡斯的笑容
Oh, Luke. He was some boy.
哦 卢卡斯 他是个好人
Cool Hand Luke, hell!
臭牌卢卡斯 妈的!
He's a natural born world-shaker!
他是个天生的震惊世界的人!